Second Dish
Episode 11
How are the two omelette wraps?
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）
どうだ？ ２種のオムラップサンド
This one's with chili sauce,
こっちがチリソース
こっちがバジルソースだ
and this one's with basil sauce.
I can make them better.
（黒木場(くろきば)リョウ）
俺のほうが もっとうまく作れる
はあ？
Huh?!
Do you guys ever stop eating?
（葉山(はやま)アキラ）
お前ら食ってばっかりだな
So, Shiomi-senpai...
（創真）んで 汐見先輩
this Stagiaire thing?
“スタジエール”でしたっけ？
何すか それ
What is that about?
（汐見潤(しおみじゅん)）
そもそもスタジエールとは―
"Stagiaire" is a French
word meaning "intern."
フランス語で研修生という意味なの
It's a program to send high school first-years to various businesses in the food industry.
高等部１年の生徒が―
外部の様々な料理の現場に
派遣されるカリキュラム
その行き先は－－
They can be high-end restaurants,
food manufacturers, or even public organizations.
高級料理店から食品メーカー
公的機関まで多種多様
They cover a wide range.
It's an official part of the curriculum
to give students practical experience.
実践の空気を学ぶ
正式な授業の一環なの
Sounds like a breeze.
楽勝っすね
I doubt even professionals
would be better than me.
そこいらのプロでも―
俺より できるヤツが
そういるとは思えねえし
It's not something to take lightly!
そんなに甘いものじゃないよ！
All the Stagiaire partners
どこのスタジエール先も―
have agreed to take on students because they trust the academy.
遠月(とおつき)学園への信頼があって
受け入れてくれてるの
If you cause any problems that would
negatively impact Tohtsuki's reputation,
もしも遠月の名を
汚すような問題を起こせば―
you might even get expelled.
一発退学になることだって
あるんだよ
That's right.
（創真）そうだった…
この学校って そんな感じだった
This is the kind of school I'm in.
So I can go out to work
in a different kitchen,
よその厨房(ちゅうぼう)の仕事に…
外の世界に触れられるってわけか
out in the world,
away from this place!
So you pass if you do your job
without causing problems?
問題を起こさずに―
滞りなく仕事をこなせれば
クリアってことか？
The criterion for passing is to make a
"visible mark" during your internship.
合格基準は研修期間内に―
目に見える実績を残してくること
目に見える…
A visible... mark?
実績？
A Few Days Later
Hm, so the first training
site is tackled in pairs.
（創真）えっと…
最初の研修先は―
“２人１組で実施する”か
TRAINING PROGRAM GUIDE
yukihira souma-sama
（物音）
（創真）ん？
TRAINING PROGRAM GUIDE
あ…
（新戸(あらと)緋沙子(ひさこ)）うう…
ああ… 幸平…
Yukihira... Souma...
創真…
♪～
omoiegaiteru imeeji yori haruka mukou gawa e
Far beyond the image I have in my mind
tsukuriagete yuku shinjitsu wa mada tooku
The reality I'm building up is still far away
hatenai tabiji
An endless journey
otagai no puraido wo togisumaseyou ze
Let's hone each other's pride
kotoba nante kazari wa hadakesaserya ii
Make people see that words are cheap and unimportant
butsukariai migakarete iku
We fight each other and hone our skills
Rolling stone
deai wa shockwave shockwave
Our encounters cause shockwaves
mada shiranai sekai e
We're reckless challengers
arukihajimeta mubou na chousensha sa
Heading toward a world as yet unexplored
te ni shita yaiba de ashita wo
With the blade in your hand
kirihirakeba iin darou
Open the way to the future
dareka no mon ja nai jibun dake no story
This is my story and no one else's
Cause we're still rough diamonds on the road
～♪
Well, let's give it our best,
Miss Secretary!
（創真）まあ 一緒に
頑張ろうぜ 秘書子
THE STAGIAIRE
Don't call me that!
誰が〝秘書子〞だ
I have no intention of working with you.
貴様と協力する気など毛頭ない
I'll get through the Stagiaire
by my own efforts alone!
私 １人だけの力で
スタジエールを乗り越えてみせる
Oh, yeah?
ああ そう
Hm, I wonder what kind
of restaurant we'll be sent to!
いやあ 研修先って
どんな店なんだろうなぁ？
Don't talk to me!
話しかけてくるな
Since the almighty Tohtsuki is sending us there,
（創真）遠月学園が
行けって言うんだから―
すげえ豪華な店かもなぁ
I bet it's some ritzy place.
Are you even listening to me?!
（緋沙子）
聞いているのか 私の話を！
Western Restaurant Mitamura
（創真）ここ？
This?
It's not what I thought it'd look like.
何か イメージと違うな
How long you gonna make us wait?!
（客Ａ）何分待たせるんだ！
（客Ｂ）５分で食えるか！
I can't eat in five minutes!
Cancel my order!
（客Ｃ）オーダー取り消し
（客Ｄ）もういいよ
I've had enough.
Jeez.
（客Ｅ）まったく
（客Ｆ）ふざけるな！
This is a joke!
I'm sorry, sorry, so sorry!
（三田村衛(みたむらまもる)）
すみません！ すみません！
すみません！　あ…
Are you two Tohtsuki students, by any chance?!
ひょっとして
遠月学園の生徒さん？
（緋沙子･創真）あ…
WESTERN RESTAURANT MITAMURA'S THIRD CHEF-OWNER
Mitamura Mamoru
アハハ…
I wish you hadn't seen
that embarrassing scene just now.
恥ずかしいところを
見せちゃったね
I'm Mitamura, the third
owner of this restaurant.
ここの３代目店主
三田村です
Nice to meet you!
はじめまして
I am Arato Hisako.
I will be here for a week for the Stagiaire.
本日から１週間
スタジエールをさせていただく―
新戸緋沙子と申します
I am sure I have much to learn,
至らない点も多いかと
思いますが―
so I appreciate you having me here.
何卒よろしくお願いいたします
幸平創真っす
I'm Yukihira Souma.
Thanks for having me.
お世話になります
I see.
ふ～ん
Arato-san and Yukihira-kun, huh?
新戸さんと幸平君ね
Well, sorry to cut to the point,
んじゃ 早速で悪いんだけど―
but can I have your autographs?
（三田村）サインもらえないかな？
（創真）はっ？
Huh?
I mean, you're students of the
Tohtsuki Academy, aren't you?!
だって
あの遠月学園に通う生徒さんだよ
You might become world-renowned all-star chefs in the future!
将来 世界中に知られる―
スターシェフになるかも
しれないからね～
なんか誰かに似てるな
He reminds me of someone.
Tomoitaya
from the Bento Shop
（富田友哉(とみたゆうや)）創真ちゃ～ん
Tomoitaya
from the Bento Shop
Souma-chan!
Tomoitaya
from the Bento Shop
I'm not a chef to be proud of.
（緋沙子）私なんて―
人様に誇れるような料理人では
ありませんから
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
（創真）新戸～ まだぁ？
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato, how much longer
are you gonna take?
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Don't talk to me when I'm still changing!
（緋沙子）着替え中に話しかけるな
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
Arato
Hisako
Loyalty
Yukihira Souma
Yukihira Diner
is on
Break!
非常識だぞ
Where are your manners?!
Still, it feels new to stand in the kitchen without wearing my Yukihira T-shirt.
（創真）それにしても―
ゆきひらＴシャツ以外で
現場に立つなんて新鮮だぜ
お？
Loyalty
待たせたな
Sorry to make you wait.
Loyalty
You look pretty good in an apron, Arato.
何か新戸ってエプロン似合うなぁ
What?!
なっ！
Come to think of it, this is the first time I've talked to you alone.
（創真）しかし こうやって
２人で話すなんて初めてだな
お前 いつも薙切と一緒だし
You were always with Nakiri.
Oh, right!
ああ そうだ
次 薙切に会ったらだけどさ…
The next time you see Nakiri—
I...
（緋沙子）私は…
（創真）ん？
もう えりな様の元へは戻れない
I cannot go back to Erina-sama anymore.
I have no right, after being
defeated in the Autumn Selection.
秋の選抜で敗れた私に
その資格はない
Oh, right.
ああ お前 葉山に負けたもんなぁ
You lost to Hayama, yeah.
Shut up! Don't laugh!
黙れ 笑うな！
Erina-sama is invincible and undefeated.
えりな様は完全無欠を
体現なさっている お人なんだ
If a loser like me stays by her side,
敗北者である
私が おそばにいては―
it'll demean her.
えりな様の
格が下がってしまうからな
Hurry up.
モタモタするな
静かだなぁ
It's quiet.
I can't believe there was
a commotion here earlier.
さっきの騒ぎがウソのようだ
All right!
（創真）
よし 気合入れていこうかね
Let's give it all we've got!
Oh, so first off, Arato, you can—
えっと とりあえず新戸は…
Don't give me orders!
私に指図するな
Listen!
いいか　現場経験が
あるからといって調子に乗るな
Don't act superior just because you have practical experience!
I've taken classes where
I had to cook in teams too.
私だってチームを組んで
調理する授業は受けているし―
合宿でのスピードが求められる
課題もクリアしている
I had no problem finishing tasks
that required speed during camp.
I'm not going to have any
problems in the Stagiaire.
スタジエールだろうと問題はない
But what you said...
でも それってさ―
None of those situations involved handling an endless stream of orders, did they?
不特定多数の注文が
飛んでこない状況での話だろ？
What?
何？
（物音）
（緋沙子）ん？
（スタッフＡ）ひっ！
（スタッフＢ）き…
H...
Here they come!
（スタッフたち）来た～っ
Wh-What?!
（緋沙子）何？
一瞬で満席
Completely full in the blink of an eye?!
Are you ready to order?
Please wait a moment.
（客とスタッフの声）
A barrage of orders?!
（緋沙子）オーダー殺到
One Omelette A Set and another D Set.
Three Special Lunch Sets, please!
（スタッフたちの声）
I had no idea it'd be this bad.
（緋沙子）これほどとは…
Before, most of our customers used to be locals.
（三田村）元々うちは―
Western Restaurant Mitamura
地元客ばかりが
来てくれる店だったんだ
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Then our nearby train station
became a bullet train stop.
うちの最寄り駅
新幹線が停まるようになったでしょ
All the people taking
the bullet train now rush here,
乗車前のお客さんが
一気に来店して 一気に注文して
place their orders, and ask to settle the check immediately, so...
一気にお会計するもんだから…
（緋沙子）
さばききれなくなってるわけか
So that's why they can't handle this.
Hey, where's my order?
（客Ｇ）ちょっと料理まだぁ？
I need it soon.
（客Ｈ）そろそろ来てくれないと
Where are the A and D Sets?!
（スタッフＣ）
ＡセットとＤセット まだですか？
Hang on. It'll be five more minutes.
待って あと５分
We need to wash dishes!
（三田村）洗い物がたまってるぞ
We don't have time right now.
今 手が離せない
We don't have enough clean dishes!
食器が足りない！
あっ 私やります
I'll do it!
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Oh, c'mon!
（客Ｉ）もう 走んなきゃ
間に合わないじゃん！
I'll have to run to catch my train!
Please come again!
またのご来店を…
（緋沙子のため息）
はっ！
Again!
（スタッフＢ）また！
（スタッフたち）来た～っ！
Here they come!
The next wave, right as I thought we finally had things handled!
（緋沙子）
さばいたと思った矢先に次の一団
まるで戦場！
This is like a battlefield!
There isn't a moment's rest between waves!
次から次へと息つく暇もない
Here are some orders!
オーダーいただきました！
Table 1 wants a special sandwich,
two French toasts, and three coffees.
１番テーブル 特製サンドイッチ１
フレンチトースト２
ホットコーヒー３
コーヒーは全員 食後
The coffee should be after their meal!
３番テーブル
ビーフシチュー２ ナポリタン２
Table 3 wants two beef stews, two Napolitans,
one coffee, two iced coffees, and one melon soda.
ホットコーヒー１
アイスコーヒー２
メロンソーダ１
ナポリタン１皿はピーマン抜き
The Napolitans should have no green peppers!
The food's kind of slow.
（客Ｊ）何か遅いね 料理
I'm not going to make the train.
（客Ｋ）
これじゃ 間に合わないな
Arato, can you handle the customers?
（創真）新戸 ホールのほう頼むわ
Huh?
えっ！
Table 4's order is up,
including the Napolitan!
（創真）４番テーブル
ナポリタンほか全部あがりっす！
Wow.
おお…
Hey!
（客Ｌ）ちょっと俺が頼んだの
チェダーチーズハンバーグだよ
I ordered a cheeseburger with cheddar!
（三田村）
申し訳ありません お取り替えを…
I'm so sorry.
We'll make the right o—
Forget it!
もういいよ　間に合わない…
I'd be late!
Arato!
新戸　厨房とホールの連絡が
混乱してる
There's bad communication between the kitchen and the servers.
見てきてくんねえ？
Can you go check it out?
No way. Giving me orders?
くっ…
（緋沙子）ふざけるな
Who does he think he is?!
私に指図するな　何様のつもり…
う… ううっ！
Everything about you is too small.
（葉山）何もかも狭いんだ お前は
But what you said...
（創真）それってさ―
None of those situations involved handling an endless stream of orders, did they?
不特定多数の注文が
飛んでこない状況での話だろ？
I can't show my face to Erina-sama.
（緋沙子）私には―
えりな様に
お見せする顔などありません
ううっ…
くそっ！
Damn it!
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Thank you so much!
（三田村）ありがとうございました
Western Restaurant Mitamura
It's over!
（スタッフＤ）うほ～
（スタッフＥ）終わった
We made it through!
（スタッフＦ）乗り切ったぞ！
That was wonderful!
すばらしかった！
君がいなけりゃ絶対
乗り切れなかったよ
Without you,
we wouldn't have made it!
（緋沙子のため息）
Yeah, it was amazing!
いや～ たまげたよ
Tohtsuki's students sure are different.
やっぱり遠月の生徒さんは違うね
Yes. He has practical experience, as well.
あっ ええ 彼は
現場で働いていた経験もあるので
What? We're talking about you too.
何 言ってるんだい　あんたもだよ
あっ…
By dinnertime,
you were up to speed.
ディナーの頃には もう
手間取らなくなってたじゃないか
You're a quick learner and flexible too.
覚えが早いし要領もいい
You were a huge help.
助かったよ 本当に
はっ… ありがとう… ございます
Thank you.
What was that for?! How rude!
何をする 無礼な！
Good work!
お疲れさん
Keep up the good work
tomorrow too, Arato!
明日からも
この調子で頼むぜ 新戸
あ…
うっ はっ！
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Don't give me orders!
私に指図するな！
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Yeah, yeah. Got it.
（創真）へーへー 分かりましたよ
Western Restaurant Mitamura
I refuse.
（薙切(なきり)えりな）お断りします
FRENCH RESTAURANT EXCELLENT'S HEAD CHEF
Kasayama
What did you say?
（傘山(かさやま)）何だと？
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）ひ～っ
I am saying that I won't wash dishes
or anything of that sort.
皿洗いなどしないと
言っているのです
I believe delegating trivial tasks to me
この私に
雑務を押し付けるのは―
is nothing other than
a foolish error in judgment.
愚かな采配ミスに
ほかならないと存じます
なめるなよ
You're just a student.
Get over yourself.
学生風情が
Souma-kun! Things are looking
pretty rocky on my end!
（恵）創真君 こちらは
波乱の予感です
Third Day of Internship
Man, you were a huge help today too.
（スタッフＣ）いや～
今日も助かったよ
It was a great idea to accept interns.
研修を受け入れて大正解ですね
ん？
Is that a photo of this restaurant?
この店の写真ですか？
Yeah.
ああ
It's from back when my dad used to be the chef.
僕の父がシェフをしていた頃のね
I still remember how all
the local regulars worshipped him.
今でも思い出すよ
地域の常連さん
みんなに愛されて
Your restaurant does have a wide selection,
確かに こちらのお店―
品数がすごく豊富ですね
and you season your dishes carefully.
味付けも丁寧で
Yeah.
（三田村）アハッ…
それだけは僕の自慢なんだ
That's about the only thing I'm proud of.
I want to try hard and work toward that ideal restaurant from the past.
あの頃の店を理想に
頑張りたいんだよね
（緋沙子）ん？
う～ん
What're you slacking for,
Yukihira Souma?
何をサボっているのだ 幸平創真
まだ清掃が済んでないぞ
We're not done cleaning yet!
Is this good enough?
（創真）こんなんで いいのかな？
え？
Leaving a visible mark...
（創真）
“目に見える実績を残す”って―
Is this what it means?
こういうことでいいのか？
What are you talking about?
（緋沙子）何を言っている
研修はすこぶる順調じゃないか？
The program's going quite well.
う～ん まあ そうなんだけどな
Well, I guess.
By the way, I wonder how the others are doing?
あっ そういやあ ほかのヤツらは
どうなってるのかな？
I wonder what kind of restaurants they ended up in?
どんな店に行ってんだろうな？
I'm sure Erina-sama is doing well,
（緋沙子）えりな様は
立派にやっておられるはずだ
even without me.
私などがいなくとも
Wonderful, Chef!
（男性客）すばらしいよ シェフ
The dishes have been refined above and beyond what they used to be!
今までよりも
圧倒的に洗練されている
The redesigned course menu
is novel and bold too! Perfect!
コースの構成も新鮮かつ大胆
パーフェクトだ
これなら来年は星も確実だよ
With this, you'll get
a Michelin star next year for sure!
Th-Thank you. It's an honor.
あ… はあ 恐れ入ります
ぐぐ… むむむ…
ウフッ
Erina-sama, please check the taste!
（コックＡ）
えりな様 味のチェックを
Erina-sama, sorry to keep
you waiting on the prep work!
（コックＢ）えりな様
下ごしらえ お待たせしました
Saucier, you are 50 seconds behind schedule.
ソーシエの方
作業が50秒遅れていてよ
（コックＣ）すみません
Sorry!
Good.
よろしい　お客様にお出しして
Please serve it to the customers.
（コックＤ）はい
Yes, ma'am!
My castle... was taken over...
by that little bitch
（傘山）俺の城が…
あんな小娘に
before I even knew it.
あっという間に掌握された
Chef Kasayama.
（えりな）傘山シェフ
（傘山）あ…
About the main dish...
（えりな）
メインディッシュに
ついてですが―
I believe the texture can be improved if it is poached at a slightly lower temperature.
ポシェする際 今より少々
火加減を抑えたほうが―
素材の食感を生かせると思いますわ
There are about twelve other issues I'd like to discuss with you.
ほかにも12点ほど
申し上げたいことが
Would that be all right?
意見させていただいても
よろしくて？
ううう… くくっ…
むむむ…
Please do.
…お願いします
Then first, regarding the hors d'oeuvre...
（えりな）
ではまず オードブルに関して
There has to be something I can do too.
（恵）私にも何かできることは？
Man, this just isn't cutting it.
（創真）
う～ん やっぱし こんなんじゃなぁ
That again?
まだそんなことを言っているのか
What do you find lacking?
何が不満なのだ？
They make solid food, their staff are all nice,
and they care about their restaurant.
味は確かだし
スタッフも皆 優しくて―
店を大事に思ってる
I want to help them as much as I can.
私はできる限り
あの店の力になりたいと思う
Hey...
（創真）お前さ
このままで本当にいいのか？
Is this good enough for you?
えっ？
Huh?
That restaurant isn't where
you really want to be, right?
お前が本当にいたい場所って
そこじゃねえだろ？
I think that the restaurant has to change.
あの店は
変わらなきゃダメだと思う
Besides...
それに…
Well, never mind.
まあ いいや んじゃな
明日もよろしく
Anyway, see you tomorrow!
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Fourth Day of Internship
Good morning, Arato-san.
Western Restaurant Mitamura
（三田村）
おはよう 新戸さん
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Please take care of the delivery slips today.
今日は伝票整理 頼むね
Yes, sir. I'm already on it.
はい もう進めてますので
Okay, thank you!
じゃあ よろしく
（ドアの閉まる音）
This restaurant has to change?
（緋沙子）
この店が変わらなきゃダメ…
一体 何だと言うんだ　幸平創真
What do you mean by that,
Yukihira Souma?
That restaurant isn't where
you really want to be, right?
お前が本当にいたい場所って
そこじゃねえだろ？
フン あの男の言うことだ
Remember who he is.
See?
見ろ 現に売り上げや
クレーム件数は―
Ever since we came, sales have gone up, and complaints have gone down.
私たちが来てから…
はっ！ 私たちが―
When... we leave...
いなくなったら…
Right.
（創真）そう
（緋沙子）あっ！
They'll be right back where they started.
今までと同じ状態に逆戻りだ
えっ？
Of course, adding more bodies during crunch
time will help keep the restaurant running,
（創真）そりゃ忙しかったら―
臨時で人を投入すれば
店は回るだろうけどさ
but it doesn't really solve the root problem.
根本的な解決にはならないだろ？
う～ん このままでいいのかなぁ
Should we let things stay the way they are?
ああ～っ
We're holding an emergency meeting!
緊急会議を開きます！
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
If I don't do something, the Stagiaire will end
with me only having done trivial tasks.
（恵）このままじゃ雑務だけで
スタジエールが終わっちゃう
I can't do anything amazing like Nakiri-san,
薙切さんみたいに
すごいことはできないけど―
but I have to be more useful!
私も もっと役に立たなくちゃ
Here's the next batch!
（コックＥ）次 頼むよ
Oh, okay!
（恵）あっ はい！
あ…
On Break
Let's advertise a part-time job right now!
（スタッフＡ）
今からバイトの募集をかけましょう
On Break
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
We have to find new help before the Tohtsuki students leave!
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
遠月の２人がいなくなる前に
新しい人手を増やさないと
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
EMERGENCY STAFF MEETING
the
Future Direction
of
Western Restaurant Mitamura
But do you think we can easily find people who can fill their shoes?
でも彼らの穴を埋めるバイトが
簡単に見つかると思うか？
ああ…
Should we cut down the menu?
メニューを絞るべきでしょうか？
（スタッフのどよめき）
The large menu has become a liability.
（緋沙子）豊富な品数が
逆に足かせになっています
If you print a new menu, keeping only the customers' favorites—
人気のあるメニューだけを残して
刷新すれば…
No!
そんな！
There are recipes in there
from my grandfather's day!
祖父の代から受け継いだ
レシピだってあるんだよ
If you keep on the way you have,
this restaurant will eventually go under—
現状のままでは
この店はいつか―
Hey, we're grateful for your help and all.
（緋沙子）破綻を…
（スタッフＢ）あのね
あなたたちが来てくれて
助かってはいるけど
But making such a huge change...
そこまで変えるのはちょっと…
We've been working here
since the previous owner's time.
俺たちは先代の頃から
ここで働いてるんだ
If we change the menu,
it wouldn't be Mitamura anymore.
メニューを変えたら
もう三田村じゃなくなるよ
But don't you feel sorry for the customers?
でも お客さんたち
かわいそうじゃないっすか
Even though they chose this place to come into,
せっかくこの店を
選んで入ってきたのに―
they can't get the food they ordered. It's not even about the taste.
うまい まずい以前に―
料理すら出ないって
そりゃないでしょ
That's unacceptable!
（スタッフたち）ああ…
Mitamura-san.
（創真）三田村さん
（三田村）あ…
What kind of restaurant
do you want this place to be?
ここをどんな店にしたいっすか？
え…
There's something I want you to consider.
（創真）１つ聞いてもらいたい事が
あるんですけど
Excuse me.
（恵）すみません
Hello?
あの…
ああ？
What?
About the second course, the fish salad...
コース２皿目の―
サラダ仕立ての
魚料理についてなんですが
What, you too?!
何だ お前まで！
Go back to washing dishes!
おとなしく皿洗ってろ！
Okay, sorry!
はい～ ごめんなさい～
It's fine.
いいわ 言ってごらんなさい
Tell us.
（傘山）あっ… くくく… ぐぐっ
Um...
え～と かけるソースの量を―
I thought it'd be nice if customers could choose how much sauce they want to pour on.
お客様が自由に
選べたらいいと思って
The dishes that come in either tend to have a lot of leftover sauce,
下がってきたお皿を見ると―
ソースが結構余っていたり
or, if customers used bread
to soak up the sauce,
逆にパンに付けて食べた
お客様のお皿は―
a lot of leftover vegetables.
野菜のほうが
残っていたりしたんです
She found something to improve,
just from washing dishes?
（えりな）皿洗いの作業だけで―
その改善点に
たどり着いたというの？
But it might be difficult to do.
でも難しいですよね
ホールにも厨房にも
手間が増えちゃうし
It'll mean more work for the hall and kitchen staff.
No.
（えりな）いいえ
Serving the sauce in a saucière
ソースをソーシエールに入れて
給仕する方法は―
has been a widespread practice
in France for a long time.
フランスでも
古くから広まっていました
Reverting to such a tradition
may actually be quite novel.
トラディショナルな趣向として
逆に目新しいかもしれませんわ
Cut it out already!
いい加減にしろぉ！
The customers are coming
here to eat my food!
客は俺の料理を食いに来てるんだ
Who cares about the amount of sauce—
ソースの量なんか…
Um, Chef!
（ボーイ）あの シェフ！
What?!
ああ？
A customer's requesting more sauce.
お客様から
ソースがもっと欲しいと…
あ…
（恵）ああ…
（えりな）ウフッ
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Thank you! Please come again!
（三田村）またのご来店を
Western Restaurant Mitamura
ありがとうございました
Due to recent circumstances, we
are changing to reservations only.
Thank you for your patronage,
Western Restaurant Mitamura
Going to reservations only?!
（三田村）完全予約制だって？
Mitamura's food is good.
There's no questioning that.
三田村の料理はうまい
それは間違いないっす
Thanks to your careful work and the large menu, customers are always satisfied.
丁寧な仕事と―
豊富なメニューのおかげで
満足感も高い
But those virtues have faded
けど今 周りの状況が
昔と変わって―
because of the changes in the area.
その良さが
かすんじまってますよね
So I think this is a possible
option for you to take.
だから こういう選択肢も
あるのかなっと
It's too bad for customers
trying to drop in, but...
飛び入りのお客には
申し訳ねえけど
Reservations only, huh?
完全予約制ねえ
It's easy to say,
but will it actually work?
口で言うのは簡単だけど―
うまくいくもんでしょうか？
It's a huge risk to turn away customers who find their way to our door.
せっかく流れてきてる客を
失うのはリスクがデカいぞ
Why do we now suddenly have to change how we've been doing things?
（スタッフＢ）今までずっと
同じやり方だったのに―
急に変えるのは…
If the circumstances have changed,
（緋沙子）
現状が変わったのならば―
and you don't also change,
you won't be able to move forward!
自らも変わらなければ
進む道は閉ざされます
If there is something
you really want to pursue,
本当に
貫きたいものがあるならば―
you should cling to it without
worrying about appearances!
体面など構わず
しがみつくべきです
I believe this restaurant has great potential.
この店には可能性があると思います
I want to believe that.
私は それを信じたい
Well, we won't be the ones
who make that decision.
（創真）まっ 決めるのは
あくまで俺らじゃない
It's the man at the top,
right? Mitamura-san?
トップに立ってる人でしょ
三田村さん
What is it you want to pursue as the chef?
シェフとして
貫きたいものは何すか？
ようこそ！
Welcome!
清水さん
ご予約ありがとうございます
Shimizu-san, thank you
for the reservation!
Hey, sorry for not coming by for a while.
（清水(しみず)）いやあ～
ご無沙汰して悪かったね
It seemed really busy recently,
何だか最近 忙しそうだったから
ちょっと足が遠のいちゃってさ
so I found it hard to drop in.
Now that you're only allowing reservations,
I came rushing back!
予約制になったって聞いて
飛んできちゃったよ
I want the usual Napolitan
and two side dishes.
いつものナポリタンと
サイドメニュー２品
Oh, and...
ああ それと…
Cut back a bit on the salt, right?
塩分少な目 ですね？
ハハッ！
さすが分かってるね ３代目
You know me,
third-generation chef!
Thank you for waiting.
（創真）お待たせしました
う～ん
ハハ… やっぱり―
Oh, yes.
The food here tastes just
as good as I remember.
ここの味はいいねえ
May I have coffee afterward, as well?
食後にコーヒーをもらおうかな
Of course.
かしこまりました
Western Restaurant Mitamura
It seems they've overcome one of the criteria for passing the Stagiaire.
（西園和音(にしぞのかずね)）
スタジエールで
試されるポイントを―
Western Restaurant Mitamura
TOHTSUKI ACADEMY ACADEMIC AFFAIRS DIVISION
Nishizono Kazue
まず１つ
乗り越えたようだな
It's not just enough
to handle the job you were given.
与えられた仕事を
漫然とこなすだけでは論外だ
You have to figure out what you can do to improve the restaurant and take action.
店のために何ができるかを
模索し行動する
That's the first step in the Stagiaire.
スタジエールの第１歩は
そこから始まるのだ
You were looking pretty blue on the first day,
but you look like you're feeling a bit better now.
初日はしょぼくれた顔してたのに
ちっとはマシになったな
Hmph.
フン 無駄口をたたいている
暇があるなら―
If you have time to waste in idle talk,
you can work harder, Yukihira Souma!
キリキリ働け 幸平創真
Glad you liked it!
御粗末様！
It's, "Thank you! Please come again!"
“ありがとうございました
またのご来店を”だろ
Don't start using your own catchphrase!
オリジナルを持ち込むな！
You've passed the first Stagiaire.
第１のスタジエール 合格だ
Huh?
え？
Your work was faultless, both of you.
文句なしの働きだった
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Where were they watching us from?
どこから見られてたんだ？
すげえな 遠月
（車のドアの開閉音）
Tohtsuki sure is amazing.
Information about the next training location should be delivered by tomorrow.
次の研修先についての資料は
明日には届くはずだ
Good luck.
健闘を祈っている
フフッ…
By the way, Arato.
ところで 新戸
You're going to go back to
Nakiri's place soon, aren't you?
近々 薙切んとこに戻るんだろ？
ううっ…
（緋沙子）ううう…
（創真）いや あ…
Not again.
まただ…
どうしたんだ　元気出せって
What's wrong? Cheer up.
I'll hear you out.
話 聞くからよ
I-I'm so nervous!
（恵）き… 緊張するべ～
なして こんなことに？
Why is this happening?!
You seem to have a lot of luggage.
異様に荷物が多いわね
I'll give you a ride.
乗っておいきなさいよ
あ…
I don't know why someone with your talent has been unknown for so long.
あなたほどの素材が―
どうして今まで
無名だったのか分からないわ
Wh-What?
This is embarrassing.
（恵）そそ… そんな
まさか言えねえ
はあ～
What was the score on your high school division entrance exam?
高等部への進学試験の成績は
どうだったのかしら？
Um, it was really low!
ええっと
それはホントに下の方で…
I can't tell her I got the worst grade!
（恵）
最下位だったなんて言えない…
But I didn't make my way back
from that all by myself.
（恵）でも その状態から
変われたのは―
私１人の力じゃなくて
I managed to survive camp and
enter the Autumn Selection
合宿で生き残れたのも
選抜に出られたのも―
thanks to everyone
at the dorm and Souma-kun.
寮のみんなとか
創真君がいてくれた―
（恵）おかげで…
（えりな）あ… はっ
When I first saw Souma-kun,
創真君を初めて見た時は―
I made up my mind
to stay as far away as I could,
絶対 近づかないようにしようって
思ってたのに
but we somehow became friends.
いつの間にか仲良くなって
Please don't talk any more about him!
それ以上 あの男の話はしないで！
Oh, sorry.
（恵）あっ ごめんなさい
（えりな）ううう…
I wonder if I said something
that got on her nerves.
（恵）
何か気にさわること言ったかな？
By the way, Nakiri-san,
you're always with Arato-san, right?
あっ そういえば薙切さんって
いつも新戸さんと一緒にいるよね
はああ…
What?
あれれ！ あの… どうかした？
Um, is something wrong?!
Hisako...
（えりな）緋沙子…
See, Hisako?
（えりな）ほら 緋沙子
The cherry blossoms are so pretty!
こんなに桜がきれい
わあ…
You should come over here too!
あなたも
こっちにおいでなさいよ
Oh, that would be improper!
そんな 恐れ多い
I'll stay behind you, Erina-sama.
私は えりな様の後ろに
控えております
I am your aide.
従者である身ですから
ああ…
Hisako...
（えりな）緋沙子
What I wanted back then was for you to...
あの時 私があなたに
してほしかったことは…
How pathetic.
（緋沙子）情けないな
I still lack confidence somehow.
まだ何だか自信が持てない
I think I've been too complacent.
今までの私は
安心しきっていたんだと思う
I was fine as long as I could
walk behind Erina-sama.
えりな様の後ろを
歩いていればいいと
I didn't want anything more.
それ以上のことは
考えもしなかったから
ふあ～あ　で 何悩んでるわけ？
So why are you stressing out?
Did you even hear what I said?!
（緋沙子）話聞いてたのか！
The answer's simple.
答えは簡単だろ？
From now on, try to become someone
これからは薙切の後ろじゃなくてさ
who can walk beside her
instead of behind her.
隣に立って歩ける自分に
変わってけばいいんじゃねえの？
（緋沙子）あっ…
I lost to Hayama too.
（創真）
俺も葉山に負けちまったからさ
So let's beat him someday, yeah?
いつか あいつをギャフンと
言わせてやろうぜ　なっ？
But... I lost. I don't have the right...
（緋沙子）でも―
一度敗北した私に そんな資格は…
If there's something you
really want to pursue,
（創真）
本当に貫きたいものがあるなら―
you cling to it without
worrying about appearances.
体面 気にせずしがみつく
You said that.
自分で言ったことじゃんか
Oh, and these belong
to one of my dorm mates,
ああ そうそう
うちの寮のヤツの
もんなんだけど―
but she said she could spare them for a bit.
貸していいよって言ってくれてさ
ん？　あ…
With Heart
I promised Nakiri she could read them,
（創真）薙切と約束したんだけど
なかなか行く機会なくってよ
With Heart
but it's hard to find time to drop them off.
ハッ だからちょうどよかったわ
So this is a great opportunity.
Take them to Nakiri, will you?
届けてくれよ 薙切にさ
Thanks, Arato.
頼むぜ 新戸
途中で落っことしたりすんなよ
Don't drop them on the way, yeah?
Yukihira Souma...
幸平創真…
Thank you.
ありがとう
Come over here.
こっちにおいでなさいよ
（緋沙子の息遣い）
I'm the same way, Arato.
（創真）俺もだよ 新戸
In the end, my cooking may have just been me chasing after my dad!
俺も結局…
親父の足跡を追いかけて―
料理してきた
だけだったのかもしんねえ
I'm gonna take my time and check out the cooking world
outside of Yukihira, with wide-open eyes!
たっぷり拝んでやる
ゆきひら以外の料理の世界を
Then I'm gonna shine a new
light on my own cooking!
そんで 俺自身の味に
新しい光を当てるんだ！
All right!
よし！　次の
スタジエールはどこだ？
Where's the next Stagiaire?!
♪～
seki wo kitta nodo kara te ga deru hodo
An intensely burning desire burst forth
hoshiku nattan da boku ja nai betsu no dareka
But not from me, from someone else
yume to kibou hoka ni nani ga iru to
Where's the me who believed that
omoeta koro no boku wa ima izuko e?
All one needs is to have hopes and dreams
nagai mono ni makarete ushinatta michishirube
Wrapped around something long, my compass was lost
sei to shi no hazama ni wa sunoo duroppu ga sakimidareru
On the border of life and death, snow drops bloom
nanika no machigai de kudakechitte shimatta nara
If by some mistake they get smashed
semete boku no nukegara ni hanataba wo soete
At least put flowers on the empty husk
konna mon ka na konna mon deshou
Is that the way things are? Yes, it is
akirame da to omowaretatte kamawanai kedo
You can call it resignation if you want
boku rashiku nai boku rashiku nai
But that's not me, that's not me
dare ni mo datte tsukureru mon ni kachi wa nai
There's no value in something just anyone could make
～♪
NEXT TIME
THE MAGICIAN ONCE MORE
Next time, "The Magician Once More."